good morning welcome to possibility in
the pandemic it is April 23rd I'm just
gonna go post this on my profile
[Music]
reproach so you want to join on camera
the link is either on Twitter handle a
crowd democracy or in the youtube
description on YouTube Ghibli Briscoe or
a bunch of libras go Jubilee saves the
world by and dream through life alright
and today why are we talking about today
so I watched michael moore's youtube
channel he released a documentary for
Earth Day oh that wasn't his documentary
so the smokey Michael Moore documentary
and I got a different documentary what
is this game it's in there it's in the
description and put it in there does
that count
I did not write it down though Michael
Moore presents planet of the humans full
documentary what's the guy's name
directed by Jeff Gibbs so basically I
can save you two hours in the entire
documentary is that the green industries
in a green industry that every solar
farm every wind farm is basically still
run on fossil fuels and quite frankly
the same people who run the fossil fuels
are running the new projects there are
new infrastructure projects and they're
basically you know screwing over the
environment in order to put them in and
not getting electricity out of them any
alternative energy is intermittent that
you can't run a city on purely solar or
wind because there's you can't guarantee
solar wind so you need a backup system
to and if the backup system is there it
can't just up and down regulate because
that costs a lot of energy for like a
coal processing plant and such so and
then basically they just they were like
humans were the cause of everything
which they seemed to think was an
epiphany
it's like I think that's pretty well
established that humans are the cause
but it's not co2 fault it's human's
fault I'd like to be where we ever
actually blaming the molecule the reason
it's there is because of humans
but that piece that our focus on what is
a solution has shifted to green energy
and the green New Deal and yet how do we
have a green new deal or anything like
that when there isn't technology there
yet it's Al Gore puts out a documentary
and then he gets all of his money from
all these the same corporations that
he's working against and the Sierra Club
whose environmental organizations
getting all the money from from the oil
and energy companies and so it's just
basically the same old single game one
game a they're playing game a they're
trying to green wash it but they're
playing gave me and yeah like everything
that is wrong with our society there's a
few fundamental things that fix it our
ignorance to what is going on even those
of us who don't want to be ignorant and
constantly seek out new information and
what's going on even if we have perfect
knowledge right even if we actually know
what's going on it doesn't actually
matter because the rest of the world
doesn't we're seeing now that even if
you are a doctor a microbiologist even
if you understand Co mid-nineteen the
fact that other people don't understand
it but that other people don't trust the
the systems that are supposed to inform
us and instruct us and govern us on
things that are that are this big that
we don't trust them costs all of us that
they can tap into our ignorant and the
complexity of our world and just push
things through without us without us
knowing that like well it's solar panels
of course it's of course it's
environmentally friendly no no like how
did the solar panels mean how how much
energy goes into it how much water goes
into it how much life do you get out of
it I mean that the soul this the wind
farms even if they were efficient aren't
are there for 20 years well that's not
sustainable because the amount of metal
that goes into them and then what do you
do with it we're not designing them to
be durable to last a long time and
luckily we're gonna do a solution
raising in two weeks two weeks faster
days so I think it's like May 6 on
energy how do we get energy as here as
watching Elsa's documentary they had one
point where they had a American town
that had had all of their their jobs
leave during that I think that they were
talking with the 2008 financial crisis
what they might've been talking about a
previous one of course manufacturing
jobs all left and they have put in I
think they're it was a wind farm and so
they they had all of these jobs for a
very small period of time and this is I
look at any project and that is what I
see I'm like how can you sell your soul
to the devil for a thousand temporary
jobs do the government's not know
they're temporary like the regular
everyday people I get it you just want a
job so you just want to get hired there
but you know it's not permanent
right like once this thing has been
built if unless maintenance of it costs
it needs you need a physical human being
to maintain it and then how many do you
mean so that you don't have let's say
they have hundreds of people employed
now they have three people employed but
watching this small town yeah if it was
a city watching a small city big town
talk about right they had jobs now they
don't have jobs and didn't have jobs
this wood fire became they get made jobs
they were temporary and now they have to
deal with wind burns if we're biofuels
like a whole big huge issue because
they're like basically cutting down
trees in order to loan to fuel it so
that's not efficient
that's not environmentally friendly that
does not make sense in anything but game
a profitability and greenwashing things
but having in with a small town there
was this like moment of clarity where I
was like like why doesn't this small
town and it's what I feel but basically
anything and everything get together and
figure it out for themselves
figure it out together how instead of
someone's being like ooh you're the
place we're gonna put the wind farm
you're the place we're gonna put the
Amazon Factory do you agree do you
disagree actually coming together and
saying what is an industry that we can
sustain what is a what if we don't have
an industry there's no industry we can
sustain how do we feed ourselves
collectively together how do we actually
make sure our citizens are fed how do we
make sure there's enough jobs or enough
purpose and resources to go around and
yeah that's a little bit pie in the sky
when we don't have the infrastructure or
the ability to do that but every village
every town every city if you had enough
people coming together and figuring it
out for themselves we don't need to keep
producing documentaries and how
up our world is we need solutions we
need to actually create great so if
we're greenwashing there is no resource
there's no renewable energy it doesn't
exist except yeah it does it just
doesn't exist in game a it doesn't exist
in our current infrastructure but that's
game a like that you have to lie that
you have to fudge the data that you have
to mark it in a way that isn't true
instead of okay it if I owned a solar
panel company I can't even look at all
of the energy and water that went into
the solar panel I have to just look at
the solar panel in order to sell it
right in order to say hey you get this
many gigawatt hours out of it right but
how many gigawatt hours went into
producing it don't ask that question
looking just here if it's our company if
we want actual electricity for the most
efficient environmentally friendly way
then there are certain problems that
need to get solved mainly the storage of
the energy which is batteries which
supposedly one company owns the patent
though even Tesla has to buy batteries
and put them together it's a Panasonic
that owns it or something but together
both we
and break the patent system in an
ethical way because we don't we don't
have the capacity to follow it just like
under Co bid 19 the state home orders or
there's now companies you're like we're
gonna sue you you're printing your 3d
printing things for the respirators that
are our our intellectual property
good luck suing after this you're gonna
sue something that saved people's lives
they were in an emergencies the laws are
bendable we're also in a much bigger
emergency that is the climate crisis
that is the environmental degradation
that is the massive disparity between
the rich and the poor and so yeah anyway
together we can break the patents the
patents so that any ingenuity is all our
ingenuity it doesn't even need to be
done in a way that's illegal like we can
when you have enough people like they do
it all the time right the big couple
corporations that own the patents and
our own most of the patents then they
find a patent they don't own if they
can't buy it first cheap as they want it
they will break that pocket they will
just make it and be like you sue us go
ahead try we got lots of lawyers what do
you got you you didn't have a profitable
business you just had an idea that you
patented we're the we're the big boys we
have the power we have and so it's up to
so the corporation's don't really have
to follow patent law it's like the
little guys that I'm with and they have
to of course fall between each other the
big guys can't take patents from the
other big guys but and I'm using guys
purposely it's named Glenn having the
system that we together keep great
things and that unveils the point of
this with with them especially renewable
energy is that I have an assumption that
every problem is already been solved by
somebody alone in their house it's just
really hard to get an idea to market so
somebody knows how to store batteries
they understand batteries yes they can't
do it because of patents but they know
batteries
there's people who who have
next-generation wind and solar but they
have to compete with like bp's division
of wind and solar and there are the ones
that have the politicians ears those
other ones have the regulators so they
don't just because you have a better
material just because you have the
better way to create energy doesn't mean
it's out there doesn't just mean it's
easy to get it out there like well if it
if it's a better mousetrap it'll be easy
to market it no no because all the most
trap companies aren't going to be
fighting against you but together we can
we can go to youtube go to youtube um on
YouTube YouTube right now
and and periscope I'm on I'm on both
periscope and YouTube right now and yeah
no I just documentary that I'm talking
about that's what JD is talking oh is
available for free on youtube there's a
description in the YouTube video that's
where probably watched it Michael
Moore's or is one there a ton of
alternative solutions right but like if
we don't prop those up if we don't help
them what we're doing is helping the
same corporations that over our
planet to begin with to over our
planet new wonderful ways right they're
tearing down fries in the name of
biofuel that's not environmentally
friendly and I think there are solutions
out there that are solutions to actual
biofuel credit like how do we use up my
compost for biofuel how do we use our
human waste for biofuel like how do we
use the actual byproducts of living
instead of creep like Oh biofuel sounds
environmentally friendly let's tear down
all the trees let's take all the kelp
out of the ocean let's there's
implications for any action you take and
if it's tiny individuals right like one
individual or a small group of people
tragedy the Commons kicks in you're
doing it for profit you're gonna
over your fellow human being even if
you're not consciously aware of it in
order to profit if we can make the
decisions together we are never gonna do
that right
together we would not decide to mine all
of the the minerals that are rare but in
all the labor all the costs to the
environment in order to create solar
panels that aren't efficient the cough
that never produced more energy than are
put into them that doesn't make sense
that only makes sense in a subsidized
game a world together though if we can
be like who has the best solar energy
out there who has the best solar panels
okay are you willing to help us help you
improve it if you want to create this
solar panel for profit you're gonna be
following game a no one's gonna like how
do we trust you over anyone else but if
we can create if there is somebody on
the solar panels willing for us to own
it and us to improve it then we're not
stealing the property from them right
they're willing to be part of it and we
can continually improve it that is kind
of what's happening with Coke in 1909
tests are opening up their their um
intellectual property right like like
it's less important that we can profit
off this vaccine a more important that
we get a vaccine so how do we coordinate
that we don't make secret you know we
don't we don't keep this proprietary
information for a decade so we can have
a for-profit vaccine in ten years we
need it to be more open and we need that
with basically everything every ocean
cleanup project every environmental how
do we sequester co2 how do we not create
new co2 we need to be able to have the
actual information and right now under
this it looks like the actual
information of the corporations who
funds what who decides what is this
actually better not leaving it up to our
governments cuz guarantee they're gonna
give it the projects to their buddies
who have no intention of creating good
good jobs or helping the environment
they're just there to make money we're
seeing it I mean with the bailouts right
now they like the big corporations are
getting the bailouts and then the ones
that it was actually designed for art
and so if we created together there's a
few things we can do we can create a
system of information that we trust a
system of information on corporations
and on technology it like innovation
that's not technology innovation of like
okay is this actually innovative cuz
you're gonna tell me it is when it's
you're
and you're profiting off of it and quite
frankly you're not you be able to see
when it's not innovative so being able
to design a system that can actually be
more neutral and say what is the best
form of energy that Vancouver can use
because then there's this this other
side that's like well our energy
consumption goes up and up as
individuals and yet we want our
governments to be able to create perfect
solutions and they create anything but
perfect solutions like in BC in
Vancouver do we have enough energy for
for our population yeah I think the math
shows that we do we do in fact have
enough energy for our population they're
also creating the sight see down why so
that other corporations can come in and
have more electricity for less and less
money it's not for the population and if
we had that information transparently
available we wouldn't be led in sight
CDF go through and but you can't say
right if we did actually need that that
electricity
okay government we need electricity I
need it to be cheap I need to be able to
afford it I need to be able to be
plentiful and you know a are you allowed
to flood the flood of river valleys so
we can have a new down you need to
figure out how to get us electricity
without that together we could figure
that out but the government can't figure
that out they cannot create social
safety nets environmental policies make
everybody happy and not raise taxes
which is what we kind of want them to do
right we want them to have this like
perfect solution like he uses no more
money and it makes everybody happy
at least we want them to make me happy
forget about everyone else make me happy
whole way to make me happier to make
other people miserable we together can
figure out things like electricity
plumbing water food food especially food
we can figure out and if we have food it
both destroys our economy and helps it
yes it destroys it in the same way
copa90 knows where things dude start to
break down when you take the profit out
of it our entire gaming system is
designed on corruption and profit and
like that it needs to flow and it needs
to keep flowing and
keep destroying the environment in order
for us to keep pretending that the
economy is a real thing that we need to
keep going like our lives depend on it
for real and they don't depend on it for
real they depend on it for imaginary the
economy inner because of the economy if
we have real food getting to real people
we don't need the food supply chain
right that exists as it currently is and
has all the waste and all of that the
crap
but if we all of a sudden fed everyone
tomorrow people aren't as desperate and
they don't need to go to work and if
people aren't desperate and you need to
go to work you cannot treat them poorly
you cannot pay them next to nothing
you cannot put their lives at risk for
the sake of profit and that breaks down
our economy but it breaks it down at
least in solitary way to solid there
anyways we're like wheat like fed people
who are looking for purpose can fix all
of our issues together the key is to not
focus on controlling other people but on
helping other people when no solution
can be enforced on the population
because we don't have the power we can
right you can't we're not making like
new legislation we're not creating a new
patent system we're just finding common
ground and creating solutions I don't
care if you're a left or right in your
politics you need to eat 90 to eat let's
figure out how the we eat let's
figure out how we grow food together
what does that infrastructure look like
Vancouver can grow enough food for our
citizens if we start right like if we
have that as a priority and we just
start without it being okay me at least
three guys and these three people are
going to develop a for-profit 3d farm
and we're gonna sell it to you if
instead it's collectively owned how much
food can we grow for our members and be
fairly compensated for our time in our
ingenuity any risks that we're actually
taking how do we spread out the risk of
any new idea new project and make it
actually sustainable environmentally
sustainable finding
actually sustainable cuz weekend
I mean Vancouver could absolutely have
3d farms right now
there's a lot of businesses that are
about to go under a lot of tower
buildings that are probably about to go
under I don't actually know what it
looks like to convert like a office
tower to a multi-story farm but other
people do and this is the key is that
everything already has a solution we
just aren't organized to allow the
actual real solutions to come to market
to get to the people who need the
solutions we can create that
infrastructure we can create the
infrastructure and the systems that
allow us to know what the is going
on in our world so we don't have to deal
with the follow of all of the
misinformation and distrust that we're
currently dealing with we can't just
regulate the people trust their
government it is done nothing but
disappoint them over the last few
decades we can't just mandate the people
that the media source is now somewhere
that you can and should trust they're
still very much in it for profit and
very much in it for citizens for making
you cry and be scared and feel like
they're here to sell you your emotions
they're not here to give you the best
news and one of the things that we can
do is create like it's I had this
conversation with someone from the South
sac this last week and we talked about
the their new project that's coming out
in in June which I'm really excited
about but one of the things I asked was
it was can we if I'm a person as part of
this I sorry if I found an individual
and I'm not part of many different
projects I want a dashboard I want to
know what the projects are doing I don't
want to have to log in and log out of
every individual project right I don't
want to have to like if I've to log in
and log out of every group I'm part of
on facebook not work right like it's
because it's on my my newsfeed a
newsfeed is a really great way for
profit for like giving
keep cuz then like if it's you and
Facebook change their newsfeed so that
it was like the most relevant stuff
instead of you could see everything
you're like no I actually want to see
everything I want to see oh every like I
want to know who posted last and I want
to see it in that order not what
algorithm thinks is most relevant
because it cuts out a lot of stuff that
ability exists because of the newsfeed
right they can change it so that it's
more profitable for them so they can
control what you look like you get down
your own rabbit holes then you know it's
hard to see the other side but a
dashboard something that actually
showcases this going on as opposed to a
newsfeed right a newsfeed is like
without any kind of graphic information
just blips of information right copa90
and Santa coming nineteen's deadly
puppet like it's it's not actual numbers
in data that's in a usable format which
is what a dashboard can it should be
right so if we care about any of the
things that wrong with our planet right
now the the inequality of wealth the
amount of whatever chemical we're
pumping into the environment those
things are not as powerful coming in a
newsfeed that is so central to sin
sensitization it's not brain won't think
it won't say the word right he's
thinking of it right that's larious that
doesn't have a bring up them um you just
can't find the word since on ization no
um having a stock on my brain it was
broken minutes it's game Brad you can do
it you can do it since it's a sensation
they're just trying to sell you try
to make you feel your emotions that if
we have an instead of a news feed
instead of something that's like what's
happening right now you can see the
history the actual why is this happening
right there's a war happening well why
what do both sides say is the reason for
this conflict
what do like right now are dividing
conquer methods of information and they
just pit us against each other we all
are like yeah you're on the other side
we can't
we work together because they don't want
us to realize that it's always been the
1% of the rich that are the problem and
yet they're not the problem they're
still just human beings with their own
goals with their own but it's them
against us again but it's like they are
divided in concrete Oz so like let's
just get rid of that without a my
getting rid of
I mean creating a world where we all
have abundance and we all have
everything we need to live our best life
so there isn't this hierarchy this there
isn't that 1% exists off off of all of
our backs right we're destroying our
planet to make billionaires richer we're
not destroying our planet so that we can
eat except that people are destroying
the planet so they can eat so that
billionaires can make money like it's
it's our individual choices on the
ground but we don't we don't have the
information to make better choices we
don't have the capacity to make better
choices because if you're poor Walmart's
your option and if Walmart's not your
option when you go to Whole Foods and
support Bezos like there isn't a good
option it's like go to farmers market
pay five times the price together we can
create solutions that are actual real
solutions that aren't leaving it up to
our governments that are never be able
to make everyone happy
and not leaving it up to for-profit
corporations to somehow magically solve
things in our best interests when
they're literally designed to solve for
their own best interests their own
shareholders best interest and you
cannot solve for both of those every
time they have a choice between purpose
and profit they're picking profit every
time we have a choice between profit and
purpose we're gonna pick purpose unless
there's a tiny subsection that's
profiting massive massively and then
only that tiny subsection is gonna vote
for it oh I get billions of dollars yes
I vote yes to that but because we're
spreading out the risk and we're
spreading out the reward there is never
a high enough reward to get the people
to choose profit over purpose why would
I choose to get 30 extra dollars a month
when instead I can get hundreds of
dollars of food for for a couple you
know for way less as long as I'm
like you can't actually well we're gonna
buy that and keep it on the shelf we're
gonna pay you ten billion dollars give
or the solubility there's a billion of
us so that's only ten dollars each right
like it's like we're not gonna sell out
our food system for ten dollars each but
one person absolutely would right oh you
want me to sell you my company for ten
billion dollars you can shelf yeah
absolutely 10 billion thank you but a
billion people aren't gonna make that
decision and so together we make
decisions for purpose for profit purpose
and there's going to be division on it
like a decision right should we make
this decision well there's some of us
that think that that seeking profit is
purpose and some of us that think
seeking purpose is profit right so
depending on which side we have to do we
have to do both everyone has to do both
even the game
corporations that are working for profit
have to still do some purpose right they
can't be zero into transportation in the
transportation industry nothing ever
gets her point A to point B but they're
making mega profit it's like they have
to do the purpose enough to be
profitable when they have a decision to
make between profit and purpose they're
always gonna pick profit the only reason
they pick purpose is if they think it's
profit in a long run you can only
actually serve one master so there are
social enterprises that are in it for
purpose but then it's really hard for
them to compete in a marketplace of of
people that are in it for profit because
we're not on their side they're not
actually owned by us they're not
transparent so we can see them so they
can't actually easily out-compete what
exists in the current marketplace we can
if we owned the not-for-profit if we
owned the thing that is for purpose and
not for profit we're always gonna make
decisions for purpose when like not
every decision all of the time but
overall we're gonna move in the right
direction as long as we're transparent
and open about that information and as
long as the risk is spread out amongst
most of us which is why we're figuring
out solution raisings
figuring out how can what could we
create with ten thousand people in a
hundred thousand
dollars we can drastically improve the
education system we could drastically
improve our own personal health care we
can drastically improve our own our our
own food system and how much calories we
get how nutritious it is drastically
improve our our media information and
what information sources we can hold the
the corporations and our governments
accountable we could create we could do
any of those things and quite frankly
once we get started we can do all of
those things and it's not about ten
thousand people deciding that they're
the new world order and imposing their
will and everybody else it's about ten
thousand people coming together and
creating a solution they want to be a
part of and then hopefully inviting the
world hopefully it's scalable but even
if it's not the next month like then a
new 10,000 people gets to get together
and create their solution for it as long
as that solution isn't impeding the next
group of people to create a solution
we're impeding them to come be part of
that solution all we have to do is get
started and keep improving it and do
that process out in the open where
people can get involved and can see it
it truly doesn't matter where we start
we will out-compete the competitors so
fast when they're soon as there's 10,000
of us and we have a process to create
anything with $100,000 we create
everything and once we create everything
this snowballs very very fast if you
imagine a world to watch any of the last
parts of the solution raisings come
together tech channel an education
system we didn't recreate right it
wasn't like well now everyone can go to
this school the school is open it's an
idea we could create with 10,000 people
at $100,000 we could we could organize
what already exists on the Internet in a
way that works for your learning style
how do you learn algebra when you're
into minecraft hey there's a bit if
there's a video out there that exists we
will find it and here's that it's sort
of to think of lichens and times tables
two times two and it goes to four can
spreadsheet but anyway whatever second
spreadsheets oh whatever
was it important just say for the sake
that we can create all of it together
rather fast when we create the education
that was a education system create a
healthcare system well again we're not
going to recreate a hospital for given
$100,000 so I can't really create a
clinic for hundred thousand dollars but
you can absolutely create the
infrastructure to be able to share
information on our doctors to be able to
share information on the pharmaceuticals
we're taking to know if they're
destroying our bodies and our planet
because we're the data points we're that
like our whole this whole brokenness
only exists because we're disconnected
and ignorant all we have to do is inform
ourselves and connect and seven point
five billion people are never going to
agree on one direction to take humanity
we don't need to all we have to do is
create solutions that are internal for a
group of people and invite the world
10,000 people can't make the world go
vegan they could make it more enticing
right 10,000 people not alone 10 per
10,000 people knocked on my door that
would be worried something
10,000 people created a vegan meal
delivery service in Vancouver and it was
5 bucks a portion and all I had to do
was sign up vegan or not I'm signing up
since it's delicious my kid will eat it
it's nutritious and I know it's gonna
help the environment and it's yeah check
that's that's my line right like that's
give us $5 per portion and it's
delicious and I can't believe it I will
sign up and eat and eat those vegan
meals and obviously agree to go vegan
but yeah absolutely
other people's might be a lower
pricepoint my Mina that has to include
me they're not quickly he's deep because
right my kid might not be blending again
which is why online my kid hey Tina as
far as Ben she's a meat eater so um
creating solutions together creating a
method of creating solutions together we
already have the internet we already
have social media and none of them are
designed for the specific purpose
Commons common the one that's coming out
in June it's a little bit designed for
this purpose which is why I'm super
excited for it because
if it anyway works like it is in my head
I'm like oh we can do solution raisings
with it we can actually create that can
be the bed that did you believe which is
a little confusing it's it's not my it's
the idea that when enough people sign up
for something it tips it over and then
that's when you take action so let's say
there's a moratorium on rent
right right what's what's going on if
they're the only one not paying rent you
can get evicted except the lovable you
can get evicted if nobody's paying rent
no they can't evict everyone right so
there's a tipping point where you're not
taking the action until you know there's
enough people taking the action that it
that it is no longer as risky that is
what Jubilee has become synonymous with
and so that's one time - Jubilee it's a
little confusing wouldn't you believe
talks about it you believe but creating
solutions together creating something
that 10,000 people could participate in
in whatever depth they want to
participate in it in so 10,000 people
aren't going to be on a board of
directors working 40 hours a week please
nobody on the Board of Directors review
for a week or I won't be able to be on
the board of directors but having a
10,000 people putting in ten dollars a
month or ten dollars total to say yes we
want we want a solution to education I'm
willing to put ten dollars into a pool
to come up with a way to move education
forward even if I know because out of
the ten thousand people creating and
it's never gonna be a perfect solution
for all of them it's not about creating
the perfect solution it's about creating
a solution that works for enough people
enough at the time and then continually
improving it so that it works for more
and more people at a deeper and deeper
better and better level so maybe we
start with an education system because
we had the education solution raising
before the lockdown and we created so
that's pretty cool but it was like well
yeah but we're not gonna we're not gonna
like my kids deletes doing school I
still think child cares know some child
cares god you're like oh actually it's a
little more feasible than normal but so
our idea for 10,000 people $100,000 was
basically like an after-school right my
like how can I get my kid to learn what
she needs to learn in with stuff she's
interested in in her learning style how
do we have a lifelong learning and it's
it's just really about like curating
Missouri out there we can do that with
with two thousand people one hundred
thousand dollars it's about what does
your family need what does your kid need
right maybe we don't start with ten
thousand people maybe we start with ten
thousand people with kids that are in
elementary school or ten thousand people
that don't have kids and it's about
lifelong learning great it's about adult
learning learning when you're a teenager
what do you want to learn any problem we
can create a solution for it is going to
be way better than what a for-profit
company can do because even if they
created the exact same thing five people
sitting around being like oh we could
totally Orkut we could curate the
information that's already out there
make a money or a non-profit they decide
they want to create a non-profit or the
goodness of their heart and work they we
could do this everyone has education did
enough to prove they're there for other
the goodness of their own heart prove
they're not there for the various
reasons as opposed to if we're doing it
it doesn't matter whether we're the ten
thousand as long as we're willing to be
transparent to the ten thousand which is
part of the deal you need to be able to
so ten thousand people what is a process
ten thousand people can be involved in
without meeting ten thousand people to
be at the board table right ten thousand
people are funding it so they need to be
allowed and able to participate at
whatever level they want to participate
at so ways for them to volunteer varies
for them to stay informed that are easy
and simple and if those things aren't
working improving those two right we're
improving the method of creation of how
do we create a solution with ten
thousand people and we're improving the
projects themselves once we have one how
do we create the beta and constantly
improve it there's going to be a group
of people that are employed to create
and run that tech project right but
instead of the current system where
again a tiny group of people has to come
up with an idea that's going to be
to be sold to the masses and they have
to be able to make it purposeful enough
that they can profit off of it enough
that they can stay in business in order
to actually do anything in their purpose
right so someone comes up with a
team-building app that helps you with
remote teams right to be able that
there's tons of them out there well how
do they compare to one another they all
charge $10 per person per month so if
you have a hundred people on your on
your there none of them are gonna meet
all of your needs you'll meet some of
your needs and it will cost you a lot of
money society needs a team app that
isn't costly because we need all of the
stuff that's going to come out of the
teams none of the ones out there are
gonna like out of the goodness of their
heart make their thing free but
collectively we actually could how much
does it cost you to run this app can we
collectively give you that so that we
can open this up to the world so we can
allow everyone to use it without it
being like how much does it cost you to
make this available so everyone can join
teams and run run projects remotely if
they need actually transparently here's
their finances a hundred thousand
dollars a month to do that and we have
10,000 people we're willing to put in
$10 a month to be part of that then we
have not only opened up a team building
app a you know like a task management
how do we actually run up a project
management app for the 10,000 we've
actually opened it up for the world
because we've bought it and released
it's the world right that's something
that could be done now right now
because they all exist already there's
already enough project management apps
that one of them meets our needs to the
best of its ability and if we weren't
involved at all they're all going under
none of them are sustainable because not
and the only way you're sustainable in
technology honestly is when you're
bought out by Google or Facebook or
become the new Google or Facebook which
is next to impossible we
could recreate and collectively owned
what Facebook does what Google does what
Amazon does what Apple does rather
easily no single entity could do that
right a new corporation owned by me is
never gonna over is he never ever gonna
overtake Facebook or Amazon because
you'd have to trust me more than you
trust like a burger or Arby's owes you'd
have to i'd have to prove that my
for-profit model is better than theirs
or may not for profit you'd have to
trust me if we're doing it together
there's a point where Jeff Bezos and
Zuckerberg in no way could compete with
us because they can't offer what we
offer it cannot offer transparency not
really even if mr. Kirk was like
actually a right transparency if it were
transparent would you trust that
Facebook was transparent I wouldn't you
trust the Google is being transparent I
wouldn't write if they were like hey
we're holding all our board meetings
live online now you can watch them all
I'd be like you're meeting secretly
behind closed doors we're literally
online I'm like yes this is how we're
doing it you can watch the awkwardness
you can watch us figuring it out on
camera does that make you trust it more
I hope so cuz like you could like see us
getting better you can see that this is
from day one you priority to be
transparent and quite frankly that is
the point that like the only way Google
and Facebook could actually out-compete
what we're gonna do is by them becoming
us which we still win right if Facebook
actually became a collectively
cooperatively owned platform that we all
could decide what's done with it
we all would couldn't crowdsource
solutions for the disinformation
problems and the security issues and see
transparently why we're choosing to use
it then they became us that's the only
way they can out-compete us so instead
of us recreating them they basically
just gave themselves to humanity yeah
that's a win like it's like they can't
actually market us out of existence not
in the beginning they could once you
have enough people in the process itself
is enjoyable if
the 10,000 people there are involved in
the project enjoy it at whatever level
they're at it right would I enjoy
putting 10,000 to put in $10 as one of
10,000 into a pool and getting to
participate in a contest for creating a
solution for education or healthcare or
literally anything yeah I would even if
that was the only level I was able to
participate
I just put the money in and I just got
information out I'd be good I hope to
use this back I don't love it do you
this is my job it's like any other day
that might make sense during this time
of copa90
literally this is this is my job I was
given it by the universal find Jean a
process that 10,000 people can can get
involved in is about finding 10,000
people and asking them what level they
want to be involved in if 10,000 people
want to be involved in a very intimate
level and want to like or a very deep
level they want to have the
conversations brainstorm the solutions
vote on which ones are going to be the
best and work through how to actually
implement the vast majority of the
features and benefits we want in any
solution then they can but but that's
not how humanity works humanity is in
10,000 people all wanting to do 100% of
the work it's generally speaking 10,000
people think it's a great idea
they want to come up with a solution
they don't even know how to call the
search they'd even want to be part of
coming up with solution but they want
the solution out of that 10,000 people
how many people want to be involved in
the understanding and voting on the day
to day and voting on how how much do you
want to understand to be able to vote
how do we keep improving that system so
that you feel like you're informed
enough to participate how do we make the
participation portion more and more easy
and/or fun engaging right because if
what we're doing is improving the
process and improving the solution
itself then we can create the solutions
you can create all of the solutions and
that is
that is the point literally everyone is
being taken care of by the government
right now no no yes yes of the bean
taking care by the government for for
yourself because I'm actually yes I
don't know what to help you like it does
not make me a drain on taxes I give more
now than I ever have before and so does
the rest of the world guarantee the
people sitting at home right now drink
over nineteen are giving more to the
world they probably weren't during their
jobs because they're dealing with their
interpersonal right there's two
with their marriage their friendships
even if it feels very chaotic and messy
right now they are either you can get
divorced or come together so like
there's gonna be outcomes and yes
there's a lot of like violence that's
happening right now and that is but even
that is like right and it's coming to
surface we're gonna have to deal with it
we're never figure it out and then
there's people who are like aboard I
need something to do and they're
building face masks and going and
working with their neighbors they're
fixing their houses and they're doing
people are choosing to do things to the
best of their capacity and some of us
don't have a choice and was like you
don't actually choose whether your
response to stress your response to
adrenaline is spike flight or freeze you
just our fight flight or freeze and so
right now under Kovac 19 there are some
people we're like fight how dare you
lock me in okay that's that's a reaction
there's people who you don't want to run
away what'a you don't want to it's like
I'm the moron can you beat inside cuz
that's you know right away or freeze
like I just I can't I just shut down
that's actually my response most most
stress which is why I've had to reduce
my stress my stress in the outside world
I've had to bring that down so that in
my capacity is now much higher than most
people for things that are highly
stressful for other people they're not
stressful for me and then things that
aren't stressful for other people that
are stressful for me grocery shopping is
always been stressful keep it before
cope in nineteen when I thought I might
get a deadly disease he's like it was if
there's lights and sounds there's just
too much activity going on now the world
kind of understands about a little bit
work
so I'm gonna start a YouTube stream that
caters to two people yeah that was that
was my vision how do we fear the rote
evil of midgets ten thousand people but
yeah right now I mean it starts
somewhere let's start somewhere
we're getting it going or doing it we're
doing things this new together system
yeah I know
so are you shy though so are you and
this is like it's coming together and it
is so much fun to be part of this
process both see like irony because it's
absolutely true I'm doing this every
morning I'm taking an hour out of my day
and there's two or three people watching
under YouTube undercurrent game a models
I'm not winning at that like this isn't
growing it is it like there are 10,000
people here watching it but the actual
things that are happening behind the
scenes the actual people they're showing
up the things that are coming out of me
just putting myself out there is amazing
other people are putting themselves out
there other people are showing up to
solution raisins and idea cafes and
together tech and together tech is
growing and people are bringing their
projects in and you can see it growing
like you can see this isn't something
that is going to be done by one
charismatic leader and then everyone
follows that model of the leader that is
game a that is what is currently being
done and then in the leader lies and the
leader falls apart everything falls
apart this is how can we help you live
your best life how can we help you live
into your purpose and by looking into
mine right so I'm living into mine every
day I'm following the next step I'm also
listening to my limitations because if I
didn't have my limitations I wouldn't be
Who I am
this wouldn't be exist like this would
be so much easier to put out in the
world if I had money if I had the
ability to communicate this enough that
people could like it could be a
blueprint that people could follow if
they wanted to
because I can't because I don't have the
money this has to look differently and
it's perfect exactly as it is every time
I play the lottery I picture spending
the tens of millions of dollars in my
head on these things I went from like I
would my man chance of it or not
mansions I never wanted five mansions
but I'm gonna buy like a nice house for
me and all my friends you know my family
to like oh I'm gonna create a technology
company he's gonna save the world
I still think that would be to go off
someone just handed me a million dollars
maybe five million I could say basically
the entire world with it but could I
because then I have millions of dollars
and then I have to market it in the same
game a world and I have to find the
marketers yeah I could spend that money
and figure that out but it wouldn't work
in the same way as what is happening and
what is happening is I'm showing up in
my imperfect way as myself and giving
you permission to show up in your
imperfect way as yourself that you don't
need to be a game a leader to lead you
don't need to follow through in the
current marketplace and refer your idea
to come into the world in fact doing
that is breaking is ism part of what's
broken in the system that the best ideas
don't get out in the world it's the most
profitable ones which means they're the
ones that are connected to the most
powerful privileged people those are the
ones that get out not the best idea it's
not the best education system the best
health care system the one that smells
profitable 1% and we're the 99% so we
can actually create systems that are
better healthcare systems than what
currently exists and part of that is
starting with the solution raising
starting with what is a something we
could do with 10,000 people and $100,000
and showcasing this is all possible
without leaving it up to the big other
without leaving it up to your government
right I'm not looking to become the next
big other we can't become the next big
other it's but they're never being a big
other it solves your problems for you
you get to solve them but without it
being you having a bootstrap everything
for you and your family what would it
look like for you to live your best life
what would it look like for you to be
connected
people who are also living their best
life and I know that sounds hokey and it
sounds weird and it sounds like what do
you mean living your best life I don't
know what do I mean I know what my best
life looks like I'm currently living it
it's actually pretty amazing like when
you just realize every all the abundance
and amazingness that surrounds you you
start to just pretty communica here me
me too
I also yes the hubs I love it yes me too
I mean like I don't think anyone's best
life is coming on a spoon channel daily
and be annoyed by them there's people
who annoy I mean I don't keep going back
to their YouTube channel like there's
but there's still something like the
beauty of what is unfolding and what is
happening in the world in the universe
is that it is designed for our highest
good it's designed to teach us exactly
what we are supposed to learn to do our
purpose in this in everything and the
scientist in me the logical person has
had to come kicking and screaming into
that this is happening it's right time
it's happy and exactly as it is supposed
to and the more that I've lived in that
the more I've allowed that to unfold the
more it's proven itself to me that I'm
now willing and able to be online and be
like yep it's gonna happen you're gonna
see it even though there's a zero people
watch at the moment even when there's
two people watching even when there's
four people watching do I know that this
YouTube channel is ever gonna have
10,000 people watching probably it's not
about that it's about knowing what we
could do with 10,000 people knowing what
we could do with a hundred thousand
people that will bring on people who
know how to get ten thousand people that
will bring on the people who know how to
do the pieces I don't need to know how
to do if I had to fake that I know how
to do everything which is game a that's
what you have to do in game a is it
entrepreneurs be everything we're all
the hats and do it adequately enough
that you can get your idea in the world
so you can then hire people to wear
perhaps you weren't very good at wearing
I'm not gonna wear in there I'm not good
at it so because I'm not gonna wearing
the hats I have to own that and look for
people to wear the other hats from day
one I'm not an admit assistant I will
not answer emails
except when I'm in my highest brain
capacity for like an hour in the morning
and that is doing everything so I'm not
answering emails for an hour in the
morning so things fall through the
cracks and I fully own that and what I
can do is show up I can show up and and
explain to the best of my ability how we
can fix our world together and so that
is what I'm doing day after day is
showing up again and again and again and
explaining it to the best of my current
ability and try new things
the Wednesday's live solution raising
and it's everyone has participated in a
solution raising has enjoyed it now if I
found a random four people on the street
would they enjoy it probably not but
that's not the point the point isn't the
brands and people it's to find the
people who enjoy raising solutions
together find the 10,000 people who are
there because they want solutions that
those 10,000 people can use they see the
vision of us actually being able to
co-create solutions together not what's
the solution I'm going to create and I'm
gonna sell it to you and I'm gonna fit
convinced you into the solution what
solutions do you want what would it look
like for you to be involved in creating
them those are some of the solutions we
need to raise right what does a system
look like that you want to be involved
in I don't want to be involved I would
stand up great then you're not involved
yet because there's not a problem this
in no way needs to convince other people
that aren't ready for it
it doesn't need to bring in the masses
it will bring in the masses when we have
a project that out-compete smart game a
in its marketplace because it's been a
better project a product you don't need
to sell them on the emotions in the
heart string and it's better for the
planet it's better for Humanity it just
is better for the planet and humanity
and you can work in your own
self-interest and improve the world to
actually use the invisible hand to
create a better world if we're not
ignorant and by ignorant I put myself in
that I know a lot about a lot of
subjects
I'm vastly not ignorant I'm still
ignorant I still don't have a fraction
of the information I would need to
understand the economics the health care
system the education system and all the
connectedness and I understand it more
than 99% of the population I'm way too
ignorant to solve it because any in
single individual is and even if I could
even if I could hold all of that
knowledge in my head if you can't it's
useless because then you have to trust
me that I did the information that I did
the research then what the conclusions I
came to were accurate and real as
opposed to how do we create the pet if
we had to redesign all of society with a
hundred people you didn't know who those
hundred people were wasn't the top of
the top it was just we need to make sure
that these hundred people have access to
the information they could use what
would that information system look like
we could create it we could create
history and science in a usable
understandable format so that we so
everyone had access to it without
demanding they have access to it right
like without forcing you to learn
science I can give you access to science
without forcing you to say history is
important and you must learn it because
I think it's important giving you access
to history in a useable understandable
way that when you need it it's there and
you can trust it because we created it
together when we have some of the
projects that we were going to design
together everything snowballs very
rapidly who is going to choose to shop
at Walmart or Amazon if it costs less
money to shop at our collective one if
they know both of them exists and they
know what both of them stand for who's
gonna choose to give their money to the
profit of Jeff Bezos instead of so that
the workers have a fair wage and we have
our goods delivered in a timely manner
like whatever our values are if we don't
meet them then we're gonna choose to
shop it out
right if my highest value is that I get
my package Toro then I might continue
this job at Amazon my highest value is
humanity is that no I need this good and
I need it in a timely manner I don't
want to wait five to six weeks but yeah
I'm okay with waiting a week so that you
know the workers are paid well and
they're not overly stressed yeah I'm
okay that sounds good and like if we're
transparent in the system instead of
Jeff Bezos even just squeeze every last
second out of the worker and pay it less
and less and less we can look at the
actual system wealth we raise the the
actual rate of our employees by five
dollars an hour we would bankrupt
ourselves let's do that let's up
bankrupt ourselves but how can we give
the equivalent value of five dollars an
hour to our employees without actually
having to hand over $5 an hour to each
and every one of them more an hour to
$25 an hour right there are 20 we had to
bring them up to $25 an hour so our
workforce could could afford the
standard of living at was a living wage
well to pay each of them five more
dollars an hour is expensive to bring
down the cost of living by $5 per hour
doesn't just benefit our employees and
benefits everyone
and so if weird trance we don't have
enough workforce we're gonna need to
increase our age we're gonna need to
compete if everyone is able to eat and
live and educate and be educated and
have energy and have all the things that
are that make life worth living and
abundance and beautiful and they're able
to have that at $25 an hour and we bring
that cost of living down to 20 our
dollars an hour
times 40 hours a week times 52 weeks a
year right that's how much it costs to
live then we're bringing it down for
everyone and we can bring it down our
society our economic system our
government system is designed to inflate
and inflate and inflate and we have
inflation we can design a system that
deflates we can design it it costs forty
thousand dollars a link to live at the
standard of living you're currently
living at we can bring that down further
and further so now it cost thirty-eight
thousand
35000 cost 30,000 instead of meaning to
pay everybody that amount of money we
and again it doesn't just benefit our
employees and benefits everyone
right if what it costs you to feed your
family of four for the month was a
thousand and now we've shown you that
you get the exact same food for eight
eight hundred we just saved you two
hundred dollars when you just save you
two hundred olives we saved everybody
two hundred dollars right so if that is
where we can focus our efforts on we're
gonna have to pay our employees living
wage to compete with the system that's
out there and we want to pay our
employees a living wage but we can come
up with solutions together that don't
that solve the problem in creative ways
that are like right instead of us I mean
one of the things for an hour
look how sometimes these hours dragged
on it's like to have it one more time
just take more time having a no I got
lost workers bringing down their cost of
living Oh having a technology company
one of the things I would love to do is
live really but with internet have a
technology company meet a intentional
community or an intentional rural
community right I want to I want a
garden I want to have animals I want to
I want to live in a small community that
is also creating the technology for the
world if that was also other people's
vision we could absolutely run a
technology company for less and less
money right because we're not looking to
pay people a hundred 150 thousand
dollars a year in order to out-compete
Google who is going to entice the best
workers to come work for them we have a
bigger mission a vision of creating a
world that works for everyone so we're
already going to get the best employees
because we're gonna get ones that are
under that vision but if they have to
take a vow of poverty to come work for
us that's not gonna fly so what we can
do is we could have a community where
it's like right come live here this is
you know it's like signing up for a
lifetime to sign up for a year right
coders Without Borders you're coming
you're working you're you're doing this
and we're providing everything for you
plus a stipend would that work
I don't
oh it would depend does is that enticing
to tech workers right is this something
they would want to do if it isn't we'd
have to increase the stipend or increase
the luxury of what what the lifestyle
looks like in our commune but instead of
finding ten workers and paint each of
the 150,000 which is what Google would
have to do to get 10 workers working our
project we can say hey we have a hundred
and fifty thousand dollars a year to pay
everyone know clearly no one can afford
to live off of $15,000 a year but ten
people can be per ten families can be
provided for four hundred and fifty
thousand when we're living off the land
when we're doing the labor when we're
doing this so it is this entice people
right like we can keep looking at
solutions without imposing them if that
doesn't work for people we can't mandate
that you legally have to come into a
technology company does this does this
package look good to you do you want to
come and be involved do you want to
bring your kids and your family and come
and live on a rural place and have your
needs provided for you for a year if
that doesn't work for you you're not
going to come if it works for you're
gonna come and you're gonna provide if
there's an if there's ten of them if
that's the number we needed then we can
create something we can create it if
Google did that they would be brought
out of town right like if Google was
like yeah just tell more for us for free
I mean that's called internship you get
in trouble but if we were like hey we're
tech workers we need to know how to
provide for ourselves we're gonna start
this community we're gonna put our labor
in and we're gonna figure out how to
bring our cost of living down further
and further we absolutely could and that
is the level we want to do it at is the
level of the community the level of can
we do this and how do we actually
implement it and any idea has to be
enticing enough to bring in enough
people to make it feasible that's okay
we are at the our mark I will be back
tomorrow for coaching we're gonna do our
relationship with self I'll be again
coach you myself and I'm attempting
today to scan all of the documents I
would need so if you're not on YouTube
come watch it on YouTube because it will
be the place where you can actually
follow along ends download the material
my channel is called Jubilee
saves the world by me entering through
life on YouTube the whole almost hundred
fifty subscribers and yeah that is not
successful under game a fun under game
be under what is actually unfolding its
unfolding and I get to participate in it
and that is like payments in and of
itself me to Shiloh I would totally also
buy the property the truth is is if we
had ten thousand people I guarantee you
one of them probably like owns a
property they play come build it here
sure especially most like a tiny house
place you could actually move you pissed
off them just move to another one when
they kick you out his there's of course
power and privilege that comes with like
owning the property but anyway yes there
is so much stuff we can do when we work
together we can give the structure and
that is what we were doing what we were
creating thanks for hanging out and I
will see you all tomorrow